<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>index on Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in index on Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:32:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Randy Shoup: Performance Culture</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/randy_shoup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/randy_shoup/</guid>
      <description>Randy took the time to talk through High Performance Culture, and how to build and scale it. This was my favourite talk of the conference.
Randy went through a lot of material verrry quickly, but all of it was super interesting.
Initially he basically talked through the accelerate [accelerate] book at a super high level, and the key notes he took which lead into his points in the rest of the talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Walker: Zombie Apocalypse</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/andy_walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 15:59:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/andy_walker/</guid>
      <description>The naming of this presentation initially put me off, as it seemed somewhat outside of the nature of the conference. However, How to Survive the Zombie Apocalypse ended up being a useful forewarning &amp;amp; guide on how to manage oneself throughout your career, and how to help others with this.
The majority of the presentation seemed common sense, however these were the points which are not always focused on and unless you begin to think about them, are not clear - you can struggle to see where you can help yourself if you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking from outside an isolated perspective of yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Wardley: Maps</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/simon_wardley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/simon_wardley/</guid>
      <description>Hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen this presentation, but had heard it was good from colleagues. Having watched a few times, he is a very confident talker who keeps you engaged at all times.
The main thing I took away from the talk was how clear and concise his observations, comments, and articulations were. It was a well put together piece, which has probably been practiced across the land!
Whether this was due to the Wardley Maps or his own charisma, I can&amp;rsquo;t comment, but imagine it would be both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trisha Gee: Buzzzwords</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/trisha_gee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/trisha_gee/</guid>
      <description>Trisha was talking about how to improve your career by being aware of buzzwords and key phrases. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much to deceive people by pretending that you knew what you were talking about, but to be aware of what the current trends are so that you can pay attention when you notice interesting articles with those buzzwords.
The majority of the talk was around picking out interesting articles, saving them to a close to hand reading app, like Pocket, or Medium, which allow you save the articles for later reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Sieglman: Microservice</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/ben_sieglman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 15:59:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/qcon_notes/ben_sieglman/</guid>
      <description>Ben was an engineer at Google since the early years (2003),
I didn&amp;rsquo;t really listen to this much
 Video Link: https://www.infoq.com/presentations/google-lessons-microservices/?itm_source=infoq&amp;amp;itm_medium=QCon_EarlyAccessVideos&amp;amp;itm_campaign=QConLondon2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home_page</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/home/home_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:30:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/home/home_page/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>