<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Notes on Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Notes on Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:32:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Wardley: Map Notes</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/wardley_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/wardley_maps/</guid>
      <description>This is an extension of the Wardley Maps talk I have mentioned in the QCon section, and largely comes from Simon&amp;rsquo;s extensive book in the creative commons as he called it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boiling Frogs</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/boiling_frogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/boiling_frogs/</guid>
      <description>This paper is on tackling the inertia &amp;amp; collaboration issues commonly found in government organisations. These are being seen as a blockers to building a transformative company that can react to change at the pace required.
What is Value? A lot of &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo; seems to be traditionally monitored by work output, which really masks the real focus of productivity which is the actual output to the customer, for example delivering a feature which allows a customer to do a task in half the time, rather than delivering five features of which no tangible customer value can be associated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/whoisboredofwfh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/whoisboredofwfh/</guid>
      <description>Is Anyone Bored of WFH yet? How are you finding the brave new world of working from home; Is it all relaxed meetings in pyjamas and smoothies in the morning, or is it entertaining bored kids and partners.
This blog is is all looking at little late in the COVID day now, but whilst lockdown is being loosened across countries, WFH cultures are likely to persist until certainty around safety in offices &amp;amp; travel is acceptable, and we may be experiencing (or wanting) more working from home in general in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>