<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Notes on Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Notes on Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:32:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Wardley: Map Notes</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/wardley_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/wardley_maps/</guid>
      <description>This is an extension of the Wardley Maps talk I have mentioned in the QCon section, and largely comes from Simon&amp;rsquo;s extensive book in the creative commons as he called it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Stick</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/make_it_stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/make_it_stick/</guid>
      <description>Authors Peter Brown, Mark McDaniel, Henry Roediger
First Thoughts This could be the most important book I read this year, given the impact it could have upon my ability to learn and retrieve information.
Key Learning Concepts  Retrieval practice is important to cementing knowledge in your mind and preventing forgetfulness of a subject. Interleaving learning increases retrieval practice implicitly, as you essentially have to do some form of retrieval to remember where you are in the context of reading / learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boiling Frogs</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/boiling_frogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/boiling_frogs/</guid>
      <description>This paper is on tackling the inertia &amp;amp; collaboration issues commonly found in government organisations. These are being seen as a blockers to building a transformative company that can react to change at the pace required.
What is Value? A lot of &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo; seems to be traditionally monitored by work output, which really masks the real focus of productivity which is the actual output to the customer, for example delivering a feature which allows a customer to do a task in half the time, rather than delivering five features of which no tangible customer value can be associated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being A Tech Lead</title>
      <link>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/being_a_tech_lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 15:38:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calumjackson.github.io/techblog/reading/being_a_tech_lead/</guid>
      <description>Notes on reading Camille Fournier&amp;rsquo;s The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path.
Mentoring Chapter 2, covering mentoring, was a insightful piece into how and why we should place value into mentoring engineers in our working life, whether it is the intern, new hire, or just an engineer in our team trying to learn new skills.
In the case of the intern, give them a structure involvement in a project which they will be able to contribute to, but give them more than enough time to do this (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>